and welcome to week 1 day four. It is a
blue day which means it is a projects
day. We already spent time with cursor,
copilot, codeex, anti-gravity. You've
seen that they're all quite similar with
their little nuances here and there.
It's now time to put one of them to work
and to do it on YOLO mode. Let's do a
quick recap first. So, as a quick recap,
we we worked with four different idees
or or plugins, ID plugins, uh,
yesterday. And first up, we used Cursor.
Cursor is made by any sphere. That's the
name of the company behind Cursor. You
don't hear that so often. You hear
Cursor, you you sort of think that
Cursor is the name of the company as
well, but it's not. uh and cursor itself
is what they call a fork of VS code
which means that VS code is actually
open-source software that Microsoft has
open sourced and you can take that and
make your own version of it and that's
what cursor that's what anyphere did and
they made cursor and so it looks and
feels very like VS code but it is a
different fork of it after cursor we
looked at GitHub copilot and there are
different ways to use GitHub copilot but
the most common and the one that we did
was using it as an extension a plugin to
the original VS Code, the proper VS
Code. So, we didn't it isn't a fork of
VS Code, it's VS Code with an extension
loaded in to get you give you GitHub
Copilot in the agent chat screen. That's
what we did. And after that, we then
used codeex. And again, there are
different ways to use codeex. One of the
ways, perhaps not the most common way
actually, but but the way we did it is
to use it as an extension in VS Code.
just like GitHub copilot and the
extension looked a bit different and it
had that little little icon you had to
click on to bring it up but otherwise
there was a lot in common in some ways
it was similar both codeex and GitHub
copilot we use them as extensions within
VS Code and when I say it's not the most
common way it's because the most common
way is to use it through the command
line interface the CLI which is what
we'll be working on next week and then
finally we used anti-gravity the IDE
from Google and this is rather like
cursor. It is its own clone, its own
fork of VS Code, a separate application
that they have built forked off VS Code
as you saw. And that's anti-gravity. And
we use that too with great results. And
when I say with great results, it's
important to distinguish the IDE, the
tooling we used from the LLM, the model
that was being used as the agent to help
us within that tooling. And we used a
bunch of different LLMs whether whether
you're aware of it or not. So one of the
ones that we probably used is an LLM
called Composer which is a a proprietary
LLM that any sphere the makers of cursor
have made. And I say probably because we
had cursor on auto mode which means we
were saying hey you can choose which
model to use. And at least as of now, it
doesn't like to tell you what it
actually uses because they want to keep
that that somewhat opaque so they can
feel free to switch things up. Uh and
and because you know they they they want
to be able to do that and not have you
worry about which model is being used to
generate the code. And so we almost
certainly were using composer which is
anyphere's own model. It's what they
call a fast frontier model, which means
it is considered a leading model, but of
the sort of small fast camp. It
generates stuff really quickly. It has
an ordinary 200,000 context size, which
is which is fairly usual, the same as
Claude. Uh, and uh, it's it's seen as a
lower-end but very quick model. And
that's probably what we used with
Cursor. We also probably used Claude
Haiku 4.5, which is the name of the Fast
Frontier model from Anthropic. It's the
smallest, fastest of the new models from
Anthropic. You might have a higher
number by the time you're watching this,
but probably still with with Haiku. Uh
it also has a 200,000 context and it's
probably quite similar to Composer. Uh
perhaps a bit more powerful. And that is
one that we we were also on auto mode
with Copilot and so we don't know for
sure. It might have been using Claude
Sonnet 4.5 which is a more powerful
model perhaps also from Anthropic. Uh
that's that would be an another one.
Then when we used codeex we did of
course use a version of GPT 5.2 the
strongest model for me and we used a
special version that's called
GP25.2-codeex.
It's confusing because codeex is in both
places, but it's because it's been it's
been specially trained to be really good
at being used within codeex for
generating code. That's what we used
that has a 272,000 context window and
it's a really really great model and and
sure it works really well for us. And
last but definitely not least, we had
Gemini 3 Pro, the strongest version of
Google's models. At least for me, it's a
top Frontier model. They have a they
have a fast frontier called Gemini 3
Flash that you might have used, but
Gemini 3 Pro and and Flash, they both
have a million context window, a huge
context window. They are very powerful
models. It's perhaps not considered as
strong as GBT 5.2 codecs, but it has a
much longer context window, which gives
it other benefits. So, they are both
perhaps neck andneck when it comes to
their overall usefulness for this kind
of practice. So it's it's important to
distinguish between the four different
IDEEs we used or IDE plugins and the
four different models and the different
IDs most of them can hook up to all of
those models like except composer is
only available in cursor of course but
generally you can switch around the
models as you saw if you're paying for a
plan where you can pick a more expensive
model then you can do so so there is
this this idea that there is two
decisions to be made which IDE which
tooling do you feel comfort comfortable
working in and they're much of a
muchness. You know, they have maybe one
has an agents.mmd and the other has
agent/
rules, whatever. There's a few different
bits and pieces here and there, but
they're basically an agentic platforms
that let you repeatedly call an LLM in a
loop to achieve a goal with tools.
That's what they're each doing. And then
what really matters, the big decision is
what LLM are you using to to actually
make the decisions? And that is where
you want to spend your time and choose
your your your money wisely. And on that
note, I've got some practical rules of
thumb of things to keep in mind when
you're making a decision about the model
to pick. Uh first of all, I would
personally uh always tend to favor a
smart model over a fast model. Uh I
would rather wait and let it do uh give
an accurate highquality answer than let
it rattle something off and then find
that it's broken and then iterate and
it's broken. I I I tend to find that
it's a more pleasant experience and
ultimately you get to a faster outcome
if you favor intelligence over speed. I
would also suggest set a budget for
whatever work you're doing and then try
and pick the most the most intelligent
model that your budget supports. Uh I
find that trying to trying to save extra
money by using a cheaper model usually
ends up costing more because of the
extra iterations and the the the time
drain. So, so, so try and pick the
strongest model you can afford. If
you're going to have smaller models,
particularly free open- source models,
you need to allow for more precise
prompts, much more detailed prompts,
very much think like you're setting a
spec, a detailed spec, and you need to
give significantly more oversight. And
that leads me to the final point, which
is if you're going to be doing YOLO, as
we are today, when you just kick
something off and you let it be, you let
it run, then don't do that. In my
opinion, with fast Frontier models or
with like low-end open-source models,
maybe you could with the really biggest
open source models, but be be wary of
that. And I'm not saying that
particularly from the risk point of
view. The risk is there. You need to be
to be watching. Uh but but that's
probably not my greatest concern. It's
really just from a time and productivity
point of view. If you're going to yolo,
the the chances are so high with a
smaller model that you'll let it go.
you'll come back later and you'll just
have a pile of nonsense. That is a high
risk. If you're going to be working with
Fast Frontier models, then I recommend
that you do things step by step, baby
steps at a time while you work through a
problem and and and checking at each
point and approving as you go with with
your eyes on the diffs as you go
through, eyes on the differences as it
as it makes changes to the code on the
edits, making sure that you are watching
each one. That's that's the right
approach for Fast Frontier. But if
you're working with the top top models,
the Frontier models like GPT52 Codeex,
Gemini 3 Pro, and of course the the
Claude Opus 4.5, my my favorite of all,
then you can yolo and you can get great
results.